[ Music ]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone, and welcome
&gt;&gt; 大家好 欢迎
to our session about user preset
收看我们的会议
support for audio units.
关于对音频单元用户预设的支持
My name is Bela Balazs, and I'm
我叫 Bela Balazs
an engineer on the Core Audio
我是 Core Audio
software team.
软件团队的工程师
Today we would like to talk
今天我们将谈一谈
about a some of our new APIs
一个新的 API
regarding the handling of audio
用于处理
unit presets.
音频单元的预设
First, let's start with this.
首先 我们先讨论一下
What are presets and why are
什么是预设
they useful?
以及为什么它们很重要
In an audio software context, a
在一个音频软件情景中
preset is a snapshot of the
预设就是在给定时间点
state of the audio unit's
关于音频单元的
parameters at a given time.
参数状态的快照
This snapshot can be saved and
这个快照可以被保存
later restored.
并在之后恢复
We already support factory
我们已经支持了
presets.
工厂预设
It's a property on the AU audio
这是在 AUAudioUnit 类的一个属性
unit class and it's defined as
它也被定义为
an array of AU audio unit
AUAudioUnitPreset 的数组
These factory presets are built
这些工厂预设
into the audio unit by the audio
由音频单元制造商
unit manufacturer.
加入至音频单元
An audio unit developer might
一个音频单元开发者
include a fixed number of
可能会在产品中
presets with the product as a
包含一定数量的预设
starting point or to showcase
以此作为起点
the capabilities of the audio
或展示音频单元的性能
Now we are adding support for
现在我们增加了对
user presets.
用户预设的支持
These can be accessed by using
用户预设可以通过使用这个
this new user presets property
新的 userPresets 属性访问
which returns an array of AU
返回值为
audio unit presets.
AUAudioUnitPreset 数组
These are presets that are
这些预设
created by the user and can be
由用户创建
modified later on.
之后可以修改
The audio unit exposes them to
音频单元会将预设提供给
all audio unit host
所有托管该音频单元的 App
We have a new property called
我们有一个新的属性
support user presets.
名为 supportUsePresets
The audio unit sets this to true
音频单元将其设为真
to signal support.
表示支持用户预设
The audio unit host application
托管音频单元的 App
has to check it before using the
在使用新的功能前
new functionality.
需要先检查该属性
This is the way to opt in to use
这就是加入使用新功能的方法
We have methods to save and
我们有保存和
delete user presets.
删除用户预设的方法
The audio unit host application
托管音频单元的 App
can call the save user preset
可以调用 saveUsePreset 方法
method to save the current state
将现有的状态保存至预设
into a preset, or it can call
或者可以调用
the delete user preset method to
deleteUserPreset 方法
delete an existing preset.
来删除现有的预设
The audio unit can override
音频单元通过覆盖默认
these to implement custom logic,
来实现用户的逻辑
or it can use the default
或者也可以
implementations inherited from
从 AUAudioUnit 基础类中
the AU audio unit base class.
继承默认实现
These default implementations
这些默认实现
store the presets in the
将预设存储到
application container folder of
音频单元扩展的
the audio unit extension.
Application/container 文件夹中
You can use the preset state for
你可以使用 presetState（for userPreset）
user preset method to retrieve
方法来恢复
the state stored in the user
储存在用户预设里的状态
This also has a default
在父类中
implementation that's
也有一个默认实现
superclass, but it can be
但它可以被覆盖
overridden to suit custom needs.
用来适应自定义需求
It returns a dictionary that you
它会返回一个
can use to restore the state of
可以用来还原
the audio unit by simply
音频单元状态的词典
assigning it to the full state
并且将其存储至
for document property of the
音频单元的
audio unit.
fullStateForDocument 属性
In addition to these, we've
除此之外
added a new property called
我们还新增了一个属性 名为
isLoadedInProcess that you can
isLoadedInProcess
use to check whether the audio
你可以将其用来检查
unit is loaded-in process.
音频单元是否在进程中载入
Loading in process is a macOS
在进程中载入
only feature.
是 macOS 特有的性能
The host can request it but if
主程序可以请求
the audio unit is not packaged
但如果音频单元没有支持
to support it, the fallback
回调行为就是
behavior is to load the audio
在进程外载入音频单元
Now, the host or the audio unit
现在 主程序和音频单元
can use this property to verify
可以使用这个属性
that this operation succeeded.
来验证操作是否成功了
And now let's see it in action.
接下来 让我们实际操作一下
So, here I have the updated AUV
现在我们看到的是
free host sample code, which is
更新后的 AUv3 样例代码
available both on macOS and on
在 macOS 和 iOS 上均可用
In this host application, I have
在这个主 App 中
loaded the AUV free filter demo.
我加载了 AUv3FilterDemo
When I press play, we can hear
当我点击播放时
the filter in action.
我们可以听到滤波器的效果
[Background music]
[背景音乐]
I can drag this graph to set the
我可以拖动这个曲线
cutoff and the resonance of the
来设定滤波器的截止和共鸣
And here I have my preset
预设部分
section on the right side.
在我的右侧
We have our factory presets,
我们有音频单元的
which came with the audio unit.
工厂预设
We have warm, bright, and
这里有热烈 欢快和突出
And in the other tab, we have
另一个标签则是
the user preset section.
用户预设部分
Here we have my previously saved
这里有我们之前保存的
initial preset and I can save
初始预设
new ones.
我也可以保存新的
[ Music ]
[音乐]
And I can switch between them.
我可以在两者间转换
Once I no longer need one of the
一旦我不再需要某个预设
presets, I can simply delete it.
我可以直接把它删除
And this is the entire
这就是关于
functionality of the AUV free
AUv3 所有的功能
host.
我鼓励你们去看一看
To summarize, we've added
总结一下
support for user presets for
为了补充
audio units to complement the
工厂预设的功能
functionality already provided
我们为音频单元的
by factory presets.
增加了用户预设的支持
These allow the user to save
这让用户可以将
their favorite sounds into
最喜欢的声音保存为预设
presets and access them in each
并将其运用至
and every audio unit host
每个托管音频单元的 App 中
To take advantage of these new
为了更好利用这些新的功能
features, the audio unit can
音频单元可以
simply opt in and use the
选择加入并使用
default implementations that we
我们提供的默认实现
provide, or it can override the
或者也可以覆盖这些方法
methods to implement custom
实现自定义功能
The audio unit host application
托管音频单元的 App
can query the audio unit for
向音频单元
these presets and can create new
查询预设
presets or delete the existing
也可以通过在音频单元上
ones by calling the right
调用正确的方法来增加新的预设
methods on the audio unit.
或者删除现有的预设
For more information, you can
在 developer.apple.com 上
check out our newly updated
你可以通过查看
sample code and the resources
我们最新更新的
attached to this session, which
样例代码和这场会议所附的
is available at
资源来获取
developer.apple.com.
更多信息
That concludes our presentation.
本场展示到此结束
Thank you.
谢谢